<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cá đá</title>
    <description>Wild Bettas in Australia
</description>
    <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 20:48:50 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 20:48:50 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Mac aka Betta macrostoma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of things have been happening in the fish room since my last post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest achievement to date so far is actually having my macrostomas spawn for the first time! One night, as I preparing dinner, I noticed the female mac was a lot thinner than usual so I went to search for the male and found him with a mouth full of eggs. FANASTIC. Unfortunately, I woke up the next monring to find the eggs gone and his fins torn up. That must of been some night for him. The tanks current Ph is still a little high at 7.3 so I am surprised they spawned. As suggestested by my LFS, I have added some mopani drift wood in order to drop the Ph into a more suitable range. I am not too torn up about the loss, in fact, I am glad to know that the two are indeed a breeding pair. It’s been a few days since and he has fully recovered. He had been looking quite sad about the whole spawn but is slowly coming around. Hang in there Big Mac!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/images/hendra/hendra-display-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Betta hendra&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over to my hendra tank, the fry have launched out and I have two batches of fry free-swimming together. The male has done a stella job are raising the fry and I can see him being stressed as the fly are able to swim away from his nest. He isn’t in his best colours and looks a bit tired. To remedy this, I have moved the film can to discourage the next spawn as it looks like a 3rd spawn is about to take place but I’d like the pair to take a few to recover their strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hendra fry are doing well and its now hard to find a spot in the tank that isn’t occupied by the fry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sp imbelis are doing well. Both fish are feeding well and actually are on the fatter side of things. I will be reducing their feeding to try to keep them in the right proportions. The male has come out of his hidding spot and can often be found at the front the the tank. I’m really happy about this as he was typically hidding in the mosses or behind the filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say the same for my sp burdigala, they are extremely shy and yet to come out in the open. I can find them hidding under the Indian Almond leaves, or pressed next to rocks but never as free swimming as the hendra. On a good day, I’ll get a glimse of them smacking down some black worm and boy do they hit the worms hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 13:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/macrostoma/hendra/2016/05/08/big-mac.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/macrostoma/hendra/2016/05/08/big-mac.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>macrostoma</category>
        
        <category>hendra</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hendra fry</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Awesome. The hendra fry are free swimming! It’s week zero and there are a good number of fry swimming around. I’m currently feeding them microworms as I watch them group around the surface of the tank. I am definitely in need of some baby brine shrimp but for now the worms will have to do. The tank seems to be swarming with life, looking close at the rocks or aroudn the leaves, I can see little critters move around. I have no idea what these life forms are but I am sure they will make good snacks for the fry. So far the parents are being good and leaving the fry alone, actually the male is busy with his next spawn! That is a back to back spawn for my hendra. I wish I was as successful with my other bettas as I am with the hendra sp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picked up some additional plants this weekend. I picked up a bunch of Mayaca Fluviatilis and _. Again, trying to jam more plants into my tanks to get them nice and lush. I am contemplating on adding Co2 to the tanks to help plant growths. I think that it will also assist in lowering pH. I also think that adding Co2 will not have negative effects on the fish because they are anabantoids and that this reflects their natural habitats, that is a pool of water with little dissolved oxygen. That’s a lot of thining, I’m just hesitating here because I do not want my fish to die from this. My current plan is to produce Co2 from a yiest mixture and allow the bubbles to freely float up so that I can start with low dose and go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that some of my wilds have grown since I purchased them and that they are actually quite stocky. What used to be a nice slender fish has become this fat sassuage with fins. I think I’m over feeding my fish and that in their natural homes, food would be a little more scarse than it is in their current tanks. I am cutting down on feeding, I think 3 feeds a week is enough for these fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, fish are eating and pooping as per usual and there is no other breeding activity to report on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 13:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/water/2016/05/08/hendra-fry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/water/2016/05/08/hendra-fry.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>water</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Water tests</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a quick ammonia test last night on the macrostoma tank. The results are perfect, the API test kit reported 0ppm. The PH in the tank is still in the 7.x range. I assume that the biological bacteria is still alive and functioning well resulting in the good reading. I am interested in watching the tank mature with the PH swinging towards 4. At this point I suspect that the bacteria would be dead and I would totally be relying on plants to absorb the ammonia, nitrogen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, all fish are doing great. I’m particularly please with the burdigala tank. So far, these guys have not settled in their tank. They are often hidding and when seen, the pair are not displaying their vibrant colours they are known for. When they were first introduced, they were in a scaped tank full of plants and wood, they did not do well in this setup. In my fustration, I removed everything but the sponge filter to encourage them to come out. This did not go so well, they spent most of their time hidding behind the filter. With the reintroduction of the plants, they seem to be much happier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 13:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/water/2016/05/05/water-testing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/water/2016/05/05/water-testing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>water</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blood in, blood out</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lets start with the sad news, my female Betta albimarginata has died. She has
not been well over the past few days so I separated her from her male. She
continued to feed well on black worms but had a swimming disorder. Last night,
instead of floating she sunk and looked extremely lifeless. This morning she was
found dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fustrating knowing that this is the last wild female I can get my hands on
given the new laws in Australia that prevent further importation of this fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onto the good news. This morning, I discovered that the hendra eggs have
hatched! The male hendra is doing a great job of looking after his nest. I can
see the film canister float up more towards the back as the number of bubbles
hes squeezing in increases. He’s also doing a good job at guarding his nest,
chasing the female away when she approaches. I am looking forwards to seeing the
little critters become free swimmers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plants plants plants. I am trying to jam more and more plants into the aquariums.
Apart from my fondness of plants, I am also relying on them to absorb the
nutrients floating around before they reach harmful levels. So far I am relying
on duck weed to do the exporting of neutirents but I have more Bucephalandra to add to the tanks. I am thinking that the Bucephalandra would do
good with shaded light from the duck weed. I just hope that they can with stand
the low PH. So far I am seeing good growth on my existing Bucephalandra, time
will tell how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 13:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/fish/spawn/death/2016/05/04/blood-in-blood-out.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/fish/spawn/death/2016/05/04/blood-in-blood-out.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>fish</category>
        
        <category>spawn</category>
        
        <category>death</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ca Da, a blog about keeping Wild Bettas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always kept fish and kept many Betta Splendens in the past. However this year, I have decided to try keeping the wild variants. When I first saw these fish, I did not think much of them, actually they are quite dull and unattractive at first. Over time I have warmed up towards them and found them to be very beautiful and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 12:57:07 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/fish/2016/05/03/ca-da-a-blog-about-keeping-wild-betta.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saltysealion.github.io/anabantoids/fish/2016/05/03/ca-da-a-blog-about-keeping-wild-betta.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>fish</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
